## S. Sadrul Hossain

#### **Summary**

Software developer and team lead with more than 3 years of experience. Sincere, hard-working and fast learner. Eager to learn new technologies, if necessary. Willing to build a sound professional career as software analyst with dedication.

#### **Experience**

#### December 2022– Present

#### **Software Engineer**

#### **PayStation**

- Developing payment gateway APIs.
- Providing guidance to clients about payment gateway integration.

# November 2021 - November 2022

#### **Associate Software Engineer**

#### Swapnoloke

- Performing as technical consultant in various projects.
- Managing multiple teams of developers for various projects.
- Planning work schedule and distributing work among team members
- Designing software process and modules according to client requirements.
- Designing process for complex modules of various projects.
- Preparing project documentation such as SRS, ERD, Use-case diagram etc. for various projects.
- Testing and evaluating works of team members.
- Dealing with clients as **first point of contact** in various projects.
- Mentoring junior and apprentice developers.
- Working as a developer in core and complex modules of various projects.

# September 2020 – October 2021

#### **Assistant Software Engineer**

#### er 2021 Swapnoloke

- Managing multiple teams of developers for various projects.
- Planning work schedule and distributing work among team members
- Designing software process and modules according to client requirements.
- Designing process for complex modules of various projects.
- Preparing project documentation such as SRS, ERD, Use-case diagram etc. for various



#### **Personal Info**

- Flat#A3, Sixteen Holding, 322 Moynarbag, Uttar Badda, Dhaka.
- +8801885547800
- M hossainsadrul@gmail.com
- f www.facebook.com/sadrul.hossain.7
- in www.linkedin.com/in/s-sadrulhossain-71624aa6/
- github.com/sadrulhossain
- sadrulhossain.github.io/portfolio/

#### Skill

- Excellent analytical ability.
- Excellent problem solving ability.

#### Strengths

- Positive and fast learner.
- Sincere and hard-working.
- Loyal and dedicated.

#### **Interests**

- Camping and hiking.
- Singing and Listening Music.
- Watching anime and reading manga.

#### **Language Proficiency**

- Bangla High.
- English High.

#### Certificates

**21** Certificate for participation in

March Workshop on

2019 Hospital Management System

**Provider**: SubraSystems Ltd. **Event**: BASIS SOFTEXPO 2019

projects.

- Testing and evaluating works of team members.
- Dealing with clients as **first point of contact** in various projects.
- Mentoring junior and apprentice developers.
- Working as a developer in core and complex modules of various projects.

#### May 2020 -August 2020

#### **Junior Software Engineer**

Swapnoloke

- Designing software process and modules according to client requirements.
- Designing process for complex modules of various projects.
- Mentoring junior and apprentice developers.
- Working as a developer in various projects.

### September 2019

#### **Apprentice Software Engineer**

- April 2020

Swapnoloke

 Working as a developer in various projects under different team leads.

#### April 2019 -August 2019

#### Web Designer & Developer

Connect Bangladesh Ltd.

Responsible for maintaining all company websites.

### **Professional Expertise**

- Strong understanding in PHP, Ajax, JQuery, MySQL, Javascript, CSS and OOP.
- Expert knowledge in Laravel framework.
- Experience in Restful API and third party API integration such as Facebook, Google, XPS Ship.
- Experience in Authorize.net and PayPal Payment Gateways integration
- **Experience in SMS Gateways integration**
- Experience in Payment Gateway APIs development.
- Experience in developing projects single handedly and with team.
- Experience in leading 2-3 teams of different projects simultaneously.
- Familiar with shell script command line.
- Experience in deploying projects and updates in Linux based server.
- Experience in interacting with high level clients and collecting requirements / feedback from client and converting client requirements into technical design.

#### **Educational Qualification**

2018

April 2017 – June Jahangirnagar University

M.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering

CGPA 3.70 out of 4.

#### Reference

Prof. Dr. Syed Akhtar Hossain

Head of the department of CSE, University of Liberal Arts Bangladesh.

Moblie: +8801817382645

Email: aktarhossain@daffodilvarsity.edu.bd

Prof. Dr. Imdadul Islam

Former Chairman of the department of CSE,

Jahangirnagar University Moblie: +8801818729702 Email: imdad@juniv.edu

January 2013 – January 2017 **Daffodil International University** 

B.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering

• CGPA 3.81 out of 4.

### **Notable Project Works**

# Assessment Software

- Performed as chief engineer in AFWC Assessment Software of National Defence College Bangladesh.
- Performed as software architecture designer and team lead of AFWC Portal of National Defence College Bangladesh.
- Performed as chief engineer and lead developer in SI&T Assessment & Management Software of School of Signal & Tactics Bangladesh.

# Sales & Tracking Solution

 Performed as team lead and lead developer in KTI – Sales & Tracking Software of Konita Trade International.

#### E-commerce

- Performed as team lead and lead developer in rebekasattire.com.
- Performed as team lead and lead developer in kingkiron.com of Konita Trade International.

# Retailing & Distribution

 Performed as team lead and lead developer in d-retail.org of Arroz Limited.

### Signature

(S. Sadrul Hossain)